<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Puneet Jain</title>
    <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Puneet Jain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 19:56:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Animate</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/animate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/animate/</guid>
      <description>Animate is a theatrical VR/AR (virtual and augmented reality) artwork on the theme of dystopian climate crisis, set in the year 2050.
Animate was recently exhibited at KunstFest in Weimar, Germany (August 2022) and PAD Festival, Darmstadt, Germany (October 2022).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disability Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/disability-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/disability-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>Motivated by the concept of criphackathon from disability-led activism, I along with my friends (from Indian Insitute of Science, Bangalore) conducted a disability hackathon at Indian Insitute of Technology, Chennai in October 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of Birds</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/creationofbirds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/creationofbirds/</guid>
      <description>This work is a search for a bird in the sky. As our bodies get constrained to enclosed spaces in this pandemic, &amp;ldquo;socially&amp;rdquo; distanced from other bodies, exposed to screens, and algorithmically manipulated by infinite scroll of images juxtaposed with texts - the birds invite us for a performance in the wild. This performance interrogates our relationships with stories, stories generated through texts, the texts that emerge from our relations with the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutonomX</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/autonomx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/autonomx/</guid>
      <description>AutonomX is an open source desktop application that allows multimedia artists and students to easily and quickly experiment with life-like processes via a graphical interface to generate dynamic, emergent and self-organizing patterns and output these patterns via OSC and MIDI to control light, sound, video, or even robots in real time, unlike systems that are fixed such as timelines and cue systems.
AutonomX is a project incubated at xModal Lab at Milieux Institute for Arts, Culture, and Technology, Concordia, University, Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Umwelten</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/umwelten/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/umwelten/</guid>
      <description>While most of us are stacked together next to each other in rectangles on our computer screens during the Coronavirus pandemic, the work &amp;lsquo;Umwelten&amp;rsquo; asks us to once again reconsider the futures that we had planned for. Umwelten invites a human, a machine learning algorithm, and a plant to meet once again to question and reformulate our relationships with one another through an exchange - a sensory exchange where our &amp;lsquo;umwelts&amp;rsquo; entangle, overlap, and are morphed with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethnographic Study - people with visual impairment</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/ethnographic-study-people-with-visual-impairment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/ethnographic-study-people-with-visual-impairment/</guid>
      <description>This is my ethnographic study with people who are visually impaired. Before begining the text, I want to confess that I am using the word ethnography in a loose sense here. While my timely visits to National Association for the Blind (NAB), Bangalore and Captain Chand Lal school (a school for children with visual impairment) in Delhi, making notes on their daily activities, conversations with their trainers, studying the tools used by them (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Gaze Controlled Virtual Keyboard for people with sensorimotor disabilities</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/adaptivevirtualkeyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/adaptivevirtualkeyboard/</guid>
      <description>The common input modalities used by people for interacting with a computer are limited to a mouse or a physical keyboard - mostly operated using hands.
However, these devices seem futile when the users are motor-impaired or have constrained body movements. The following project is a virtual keyboard that is operated through eye-gaze rather than hands. The keyboard has a modified QWERTY layout and is integrated with a customized machine learning algorithm to dynamically adapt dwell time of the keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inertial Motion Sensing and Haptics in UNITY3D</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/inertial-motion-sensing-and-haptics-in-unity3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/inertial-motion-sensing-and-haptics-in-unity3d/</guid>
      <description>This was a small attempt to understand how wearable gloves work and what are the various mediums by which one can integrate haptics into the device. The particular glove I used is &amp;lsquo;Capto Glove&amp;rsquo; purchased from the Company of the same name. Currently, the glove consists of an IMU (Intertial Measurement Unit) that provides accelerometer, magnetometer and gyroscopic readings along the three axes. The glove has many other features like bending force calculation, finger pressure readings, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybernetic Plant Human Interface</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/cybernetic-plant-human-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/cybernetic-plant-human-interface/</guid>
      <description>This project explores a proof of concept to open up a dialogue between a human and a non-human (a Mimosa Plant) in a digital space where they co-exist together, share the digital space, and compete for their respective goals to interact with each other resulting in a cybernetic performance over time.
Introduction The intake of digital information till date is heavily based on rectangular computer screens and demand an acute visual focus (which is also overwhelmingly visual from a cultural/social sensory point of view) of the observer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Energy Recommendation Tool (NASA SpaceApp Challenge 2017)</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/solar-energy-recommendation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:57:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/solar-energy-recommendation-tool/</guid>
      <description>Helios is a tool that won a global nominee at NASA Space App Challenge 2017. Helios helps people understand the amount of energy generated from different types of Solar panels and how they can relate it to daily household items.Helios also helps the Hi-Seas crew to plan their daily activities by giving personalized recommendations.
The Problem In the past decade we have seen a great inclination towards use of solar energy around the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogy of Neural Networks - A short essay</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/genealogy-of-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:50:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/genealogy-of-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Medical prescriptions from a chat bot on a website, songs recommended by a cylinder in a dining room, and cars on a highway driving without human assistance portrays a world surrounded by &amp;ldquo;intelligent&amp;rdquo; entities - intelligence that is equivalent to that of a human brain. Indeed, all the above technologies are equipped with a common architecture, a neural network that: imitates the human brain to learn patterns in datasets, optimize its decisions, and predict results to act on the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intertwinement of Entropy, Information, and Thermodynamics - A short essay</title>
      <link>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/entropy-information-and-thermodynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:50:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jainpuneet798.github.io/portfolio/entropy-information-and-thermodynamics/</guid>
      <description>In the mid-20th century, the concept of communication that was mostly tied to a source and a physical medium was challenged and ontologically shifted by a mathematician named Claude Shannon by the construction of a grand unified theory of communication. Shannon achieved this extraordinary goal by quantifying the information associated with a message, the capacity of a communication channel through which this message passes, the coding processes needed to make that channel efficient, study of noise that could arise in such a system, and noise&amp;rsquo;s effect on the accuracy of the received message by using a single concept from the physical sciences - entropy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
